Andrés Camilo Zúñiga González

Accomplished researcher at the postgraduate level with a passion for data-driven insights. Strong background in statistical modelling and scientific research. Focused on knowledge creation based on analytical reasoning. Currently at Cambridge studying the application of AI in environmental Risk.

ancazugo@hotmail.com

Colombia & UK







/ancazugo

SKILLS

- R (Tidyverse, Shiny), Python (Scikitlearn, Tensorflow), Java, Javascript (D3.js), HTML5, CSS, LaTeX, UNIX Shell, SQL, Git, Docker, API REST, AWS, ArcGIS and QGIS.
- Data analysis and visualization, machine learning and web development
- Teamwork, group and project management, public speaking and technical writing

CERTIFICATIONS

- Cartography | Esri
- Data Science For All | Correlation One
- Tensorflow Developer | Deeplearning.ai
- Tensorflow: Data and Deployment | Deeplearning.ai
- Deep Learning | Deeplearning.ai
- Data Science | Johns Hopkins University
- Discrete Mathematics | National Research University Higher School of Economics

LANGUAGES

- Native Spanish
- Fluent English (IELTS C1)
- · Limited proficiency in French

EXPERIENCE

Trudata, Colombia

Data Scientist | Dec 2021 - Present

Develop machine learning models for costumer segmentation and duplicate detection. Deploy web applications via cloud services.

Data Analyst | Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Web scrape real state marketplaces for further integration in a DBMS. Develop interactive visualization tools for data exploration and modelling.

Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Research Assistant | Aug 2017 - Feb 2022

Worked on Bayesian modeling of carbon-14 dates of volcano eruptions and human settlements. Research on environmental DNA and chemical markers of high-altitud wetlands from Colombia.

Teaching Assistant | Aug 2017 - Jun 2021

Taught courses in the use of R and the Linux Command Shell in statistical analysis in research. Developed weekly lectures, activities and exams geared towards students from engineering and science majors.

Cornell University, USA

Research Assistant | Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Worked at the Bergstrom Lab in the modelling and statistical analysis of the epidemiological assessment of the Switchgrass Head Smut in the State of New York.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

University of Cambridge, UK

• MRes + PhD in AI for Environmental Risk (AI4ER) | present

Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

- M.Sc. in Biological Sciences Biology Focus | 2020
- B.Sc. in Biology | 2017
- B.Sc. in Microbiology | 2017
- Minor in Geography | 2017